# LISA VINSON | software developer

# experience

## Technical Support Manager | White Whale Web Services

November 2020 - Present, Remote

- Diagnose and resolve critical website issues for 100+ university websites, ranging from site outages to accessibility bugs
- Implement client customizations using HTML, CSS (LESS/SASS), JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, and SQL to improve process automation, mobile responsiveness, or extend software features.
- Design and create university and calendar management websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery, ensuring mobile responsiveness and WCAG accessibility compliance.
- Oversee projects to migrate university websites to internal load-balanced servers in AWS without user disruption.

#### Teaching Assistant & Grader | UCF Coding Bootcamp

August 2018 – December 2020, Orlando, FL / Remote

- Introduced software development concepts to students, with a focus on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Supported class lessons and hosted office hours to provide one-on-one tutoring and group focus sessions on agile methodology, JavaScript, and application deployment processes.

#### Software Developer I | CentralSquare Technologies

April 2019 - March 2020, Lake Mary, FL

- Resolved production bugs in complex finance and HR management applications used by governments using VB.Net, C#, Genero, and SQL.
- Solo developer on a cross-application feature to allow expansion of payroll deduction types and employee choices of deduction options.

#### QA Analyst I | CentralSquare Technologies

May 2018 - March 2019, Lake Mary, FL

- Authored and executed test cases in Azure DevOps to confirm requirements.
- Identified and documented bugs during each sprint and regression period.
- Performed cross browser and operating system compatibility testing using BrowserStack.

#### Client Delivery Manager | PeopleScout

April 2017-August 2017, Charlotte, NC

- Led requirements meetings with clients to determine business needs, define scope, and document new processes.
- Performed root cause analysis of client issues, providing recommendations that reduced average client escalations by 80% in 3 months.

#### contact

- Atlanta, GA
- **4**07-808-8607
- www.lisavinson.com
- in lisavinson1
- LiVinson

### profile

Front-end developer with a focus on continuously improving ability to write clean, testable, and maintainable code, regardless of tech stack.
Leverages experience in devops, technical support, and QA testing to understand users, their needs, and how to provide simple solutions to complex problems.

# skills & knowledge

HTML

CSS (SASS/LESS)

**Bootstrap** 

JavaScript

**jQuery** 

React

Redux

Express

Node.js

C#/.NET

**SQL & Sequelize** 

MongoDB & Mongoose

Firebase

Jest & Enzyme

Webpack

Babel

Git / Version Control

Figma

# LISA VINSON | software developer

### Sr. Operations Specialist | PeopleScout

February 2014 - April 2017, Charlotte, NC

- Designed training curriculum for core processes, facilitating in person and virtual training sessions for up to 30 employees in four geographic locations.
- Conducted monthly quality assessments of client's hiring process to ensure compliance with company guidelines and federal law.

# applications

### Taboo! Multiplayer Team Game | https://playtaboo.app

React, Redux, React Router, Styled Components, Firebase, Node.js, Jest, Enzyme

- A mobile-first online version of the popular board game that pits friends against each other to describe a given word without saying anything sq from the "taboo" list. Play when physically together or while socially distanced via online meeting platforms.
- Displays varying views based on each player's team and current role in the game with real time updates of actions performed by other players.
- Designed using Figma and deployed to Firebase using Jenkins for continuous integration and deployment.
- Administrative program to review card ideas submitted by players, review system errors, and import data from CSV to create or update game cards.

# Hacker New Clone | https://hacker-news-react-clone.netlify.app

JavaScript, React, React Router, Context API, Webpack, Babel

- Fetches data from the Hacker News API and displays the top and new story headlines.
- View story details, comments, and user profiles. Toggle between a light or dark theme.
- Bundled and compiled with custom webpack and babel configuration and deployed using Netlify.

#### contact

- Atlanta, GA
- **4**07-808-8607
- www.lisavinson.com
- in lisavinson1
- LiVinson

#### education

# University of Central Florida

**April 2018** 

Full Stack Web
Development, Certification

# Tarleton State University December 2015

HR Management, MS

## **University of Florida**

May 2012

Sociology, BA

#### interests

drawing

boxing

basketball

hiking

kayaking